BRANDON TOUSHAN

<u>brandon.toushan@queensu.ca</u> I 613-453-8198 I <u>https://ca.linkedin.com/in/brandon-toushan/</u> I <u>https://brandontoushan.github.io/</u> I <u>https://github.com/BrandonToushan</u>

PROFILE SUMMARY

Driven, people-centric analytics practitioner, leader and project owner. Creative problem-solver and data integrator that excels at influencing change in fast-paced and highly competitive environments. Jointly passionate about investing in data and in people, and happiest when facilitating buy-in to both. Native speaker of the languages of business and technology and an expert at bridging the gap between the two in order to connect organizations better.

SKILL SUMMARY

- Big-picture strategic thinker and organizational influencer
- Empathetic storyteller, relationship builder and salesperson
- Full stack developer skillset JS, HTML/CSS, Python, R, MatLab, SQL
- Robust analytics and AI toolkit NumPy, SciPy, Pandas, Scikit-learn, Tensorflow, Keras, TidyR
- Extensive visualization and design expertise D3.js, chart.js, bokeh, matplotlib, ggplot2, R shiny

EDUCATION

Master of Management Analytics (MMA), Smith School of Business, Queen's University, Kingston, ON 2020 - Present

- GPA: **4.1/4.3** (In Progress)
- Coursework included topics on analytical decision making, big data analytics, predictive modeling, machine learning, artificial intelligence and strategy, finance and operations fundamentals

Bachelor of Science, Physics and Mathematics, Queen's University, Kingston, ON

2015 - 2019

- Recipient of the Gordon Canning Award in Mathematics, 2019
- Coursework included topics on advanced calculus, probability and statistics, stochastic processes, linear and differential algebra, mathematical and computational methods and both modern and classical physics

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Management Consultant, Smith Business Consulting, Kingston, ON

2020 - Present

 Currently advising several local businesses on strategy reimagination, business model adaption and operational resilience development

Software & Data Visualization Engineer, Harvard Humanitarian Initiative, Cambridge, MA, US

2020 - Presen

- Identified an opportunity to expand upon the visualization and analytics capabilities of the KoBo Toolbox platform and increase the value provided to our most important users and stakeholders
- Pitched, developed and led a complete overhaul of KoBo's existing API including considerable improvements to the depth, breadth and quality of the UI/UX, the introduction of new export as .svg functionality and a complete upgrade from chart.js to d3.js based visualization
- Currently working with many of KoBo's biggest users including the UNHCR, the World Bank and the IFRC on needs determination, bespoke solution development and organizational-level implementation of the KoBo platform

Full Stack Web Developer, Freelance, Kingston, ON

2019 - 2020

- Helped clients grow their personal brands, improve their advertising metrics and drive sales and revenue growth across their respective organizations via the introduction of personalized web solutions
- Worked extensively identifying and reaching out to potential clients, determining personal needs, closing sales and developing individually tailored solutions, largely using HTML/CSS, JS & Bootstrap

Program Lead, Firefly Therapy Services, KidsAbility Centre for Child Development, Waterloo, ON 2017 - 2018

- Oversaw the successful rollout of KidsAbility's most successful outreach programming to date as lead of an interdisciplinary team during the introduction of a new series of therapy camp initiatives and programs
- Worked day-in day-out managing staff, developing and scheduling programming, monitoring KPIs and liaising between admin, front-line staff, clients and community stakeholders